Paterne MALLE

Web Developer

paternmalle@gmail.com

07 832 959 448

Leeds, UK

French web-developer, graduated recently, following an intensive one year course, including a three month internship. Looking to put my technical skills and life experience to work in a team environment interested in someone with a non-standard professional path.

Main tech skills

Html, CSS, Javascript, React JS, Git, API.

Soft skills

Teamwork, Adaptability, Autonomy, Critical thinking, Quantitative skills, Analysis, Synthesis.

Other tech skills

PHP, Laravel, WordPress, Node, PWA, Bootstrap.

Languages

English: proficient.French: native.

Education

Web developer: 2019 - 2020 Simplon school, HND Level 5 equivalent

- Contents of the course: Html, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Git, Node, PHP, Laravel, SQL, WordPress, PWA.
- Learned the basics of SEO and web design.
- · Introduction to agile methodologies.
- Opquast certified: good practises for web (UX, accessibility, security, e-commerce).
- · Hands on and practical exercises.
- Realised multiple small projects in teams of three to four people.
- Presentations in front of public varying from the class to 50 people.

BPREA Poultry farming: 2011, A level equivalent

- Two, one month practical internships.
- Learned technical and economic skills for enterprise management.

CAP Carpentry: 2008, NVQ level 2 equivalent

- · Two, one month practical internships.
- Workflow conception, process organization.
- Fine-tuned attention to detail and creative problem solving skills.

Master's degree in sociology: 2001 - 2006 University of Caen.

- · Developed self-discipline.
- · Critical thinking, documenting.
- · Survey design, data gathering and analysis.

Work experience

Practical Internship (3 months): 2020 Com3elles.

Small communication company, specialized in design, advice, and website conception using the CMS Joomla! and WordPress.

- Improved a Joomla! component (changing a data typology into another one).
- Enhanced a plugin for Joomla!, using Googlemap, Openstreetmap, Leaflet and Algolia.
- Skills developed: autonomy, research, dealing with legacy code.

Cheese maker: 2017 - 2018 Artisanal cheese factory

- Elected staff representative for 30 employees.
- · Reorganized aspects of the manufacturing processes.
- · Skills developed: teamwork, responsiveness, improvisation and crisis management.

Farmer and woodworker: 2008 - 2017 Collaborative homestead

- · Created and managed an organic free range egg workshop of 450 hens.
- Built a new 400m² sheepfold.
- Lived, worked and decided as a team, fluctuating between 5 and 12 members.
- Responsible for client relation/sales with professionals and customers.
- Skills developed: teamwork, autonomy, adaptation, improvisation, constancy.

Personal projects

Link to my Github: https://github.com/Patern14

Pokedex

- · Created with React JS and react-router-dom.
- Retrieves data from pokeAPI.
- Displays the first 20 Pokemons, load the following 20, displays a random Pokemon.
- Shows details of the selected Pokemon including their types and evolutions.

Flexbox reminder

- · DOM manipulation with Javascript.
- An interactive reminder for Flexbox properties where the results of the different options for the Container and the Content are displayed.

Sm4rty

- Reproduced the Smarty website homepage.
- · Media queries for desktop and mobile versions.

Connect4

- A Javascript version of the four in a row game.
- · Victory conditions, reset button.

Interests

Sciences, technologies, UI/UX, Boardgames, Woodworking, Ecology, Sports, Japan, USA, History.